Guide to the Mel Rosenthal photographs, 1975-2011 RL.10011
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- The Arab-Americans: Americans by Choice, 2000-2002; 2 boxes
  - Essa with his children in their store where I met him by accident when I needed to buy lithium batteries (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-62)
    Mr. Widdi told me he was mayor of the Palestinians.
  - Charles Sahadi at one of his delicatessen and grocery stores (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-63)
    It is known for its Mid-Eastern fine foods.
  - Wafta Shama teaching embroidery at the Museum of the City of New York, December, 2001 (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-64)
  - [The wedding of Sandra Hajjaj and Komenby Kharoufeh at Widdi's Catering Hall, Brooklyn, August 22, 1999] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-65)
    The gold coins are traditional wedding presents which are pinned to the wife's gown. The groom's mother is keeping playing children from colliding with the cake.
  - [Family at the wedding of Sandra Hajjaj and Komenby Kharoufeh at Widdi's Catering hall, Brooklyn, August 22, 1999] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-66)
  - At the end of the wedding reception (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-67)
  - Young girl lighting candle, Palm Sunday, 2001, in St. Mary's Orthodox church, Bay Ridge, Brooklyn (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-68)
  - Holy Communion, St Mary's Orthodox Church, Palm Sunday, 2001 (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-69)
  - Teaching the Koran in a small mosque in Albany, N.Y. (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-70)
  - Mar Nasrallah Boutros Sfeir, Patriarch of Antioch and All the East, Our Lady of Lebanon Antiochian Syriac Maronite Church, Brooklyn, March 11, 2001 (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-71)
  - Mar Nasrallah Boutros Sfeir, Patriarch of Antioch and All the East, Our Lady of Lebanon Antiochian Syriac Maronite Church, Brooklyn, March 11, 2001 (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-72)
  - Coptic Church of St. George (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-73)
  - [Coptic church] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-74)
  - Holy Communion at the Coptic Church of St. George, 2006, Sunset Park, Brooklyn (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-75)
  - Coptic Church of St George, women in front of icon of St Michael (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-76)
  - [Policeman] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-77)
  - "Iraqi moms love their kids too" (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-78)
    Two Iraqi women sit on steps at a protest.
  - ["Violence begets violence"] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-79)
    Young girl holds up sign at protest.
  - [Young man playing stringed instrument] (Box 5, Image RL10011-P-80)
- Papers, 2000-2011; 1 box
  Papers in the collection include publicity for several of Rosenthal's exhibits; workshop brochures for which Rosenthal was an instructor; a photography project music CD; and an audiocassette of Rosenthal's talk at Duke University on October 7, 2004, at the opening of the exhibit Mel Rosenthal: Photographs from "In the South Bronx of America."
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original media closed to use; listening copy must be made for access. Please contact the Rubenstein Library staff before coming to use this collection.
  - "Refuge: The Newest New Yorkers," Ellis Island Immigration Museum exhibit pamphlet, 2000; 2 pamphlets (Box 6)
  - Audiocassette recording of Mel Rosenthal's exhibit talk, 2004 Oct. 7 (Box 6)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Original recording is closed to use; listening copy must be made for access. Please contact the Rubenstein Library staff before coming to use this collection.
  - "Documentary photography in New York City" workshops brochures, 2001, 2004 (Box 6)
  - "The Arab Americans: Americans by Choice," exhibit pamphlet, 2008 (Box 6)
  - "Women in photography" Empire State College workshop brochure, 2010 (Box 6)
  - The Silverwolf Homeless Project music CD with photography by Mel Rosenthal in booklet, 2010 (Box 6)
  - "Mel Rosenthal: 40 years of photographs," exhibit brochure, 2011 (Box 6)
  - New York Times "Lens" blog post on Mel Rosenthal's work, printed out copy, 2011 October 11 (Box 6)